<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CNN</string>
    <string name="article_name">Judul Berita</string>
    <string name="article_description">Deskripsi Berita</string>
    <string name="data_received">data_received</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="namadicoding">Zahrina Candrakanti</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="emaildicoding">zahrinacandrakanti@gmail.com</string>
    <string-array name="data_article">
        <item>Biden Signs Landmark Executive Order on Police Reform </item>
        <item>Supreme Court overturns Roe v. Wade, ending right to abortion upheld for decades</item>
        <item>Google halts AI tool’s ability to produce images of people after backlash </item>
        <item>Weekend Box Office: ‘Madame Web’ struggles to get off the ground, ‘One Love’ soars </item>
        <item>Instagram and Threads will no longer promote ‘political’ content. No one knows what they define as ‘political’ </item>
        <item>A cousin to the Mediterranean diet: The Atlantic diet explained </item>
        <item>German police arrest Red Army Faction suspect Daniela Klette </item>
        <item>Nigeria customs confirms deaths in stampede for discounted rice </item>
        <item>An explosive Texas fire more than doubles in size as it threatens towns and forces evacuations </item>
        <item>Starbucks to begin talks with Workers United union</item>
        <item>Number of 401(k) ‘millionaires’ jumped 41% last year, says Fidelity </item>
        <item>Earn the Southwest Companion Pass for a year with this incredible offer </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="data_description">
        <item>President Joe Biden on Wednesday signed an executive order on police reform that he hopes will help prevent excessive force and encourage officers to intervene in such cases.
The president signed the order on the two-year anniversary of George Floyd’s death at the hands of police in Minneapolis.“Two years ago, the murder of George Floyd exposed for many what Black and brown communities have long known and experienced — that more must be done to ensure that America lives up to its founding promise of fair and impartial justice for all,” Biden said. “As divided as this nation can feel, today we’re showing the strength of our unity. This executive order is going to deliver the most significant police reform in decades.”\n
            Vice President Kamala Harris also spoke at the White House signing ceremony that featured Floyd’s family.

“We know this executive order will not take away your pain,” she said. “We also know this executive order is no substitute for legislation, nor does it accomplish everything we know must be done. But it is a necessary and long overdue critical step forward.”

Following the murder conviction of former Minneapolis Police Officer Derek Chauvin, three other officers were found guilty in federal court of violating Floyd’s civil rights.

Prosecutors said the trio stood by while Chauvin pressed his knee into the unarmed 46-year-old’s neck for more than nine minutes.
        </item>

        <item>In a historic and far-reaching decision, the U.S. Supreme Court officially reversed Roe v. Wade on Friday, declaring that the constitutional right to abortion, upheld for nearly a half century, no longer exists.
        <br>Writing for the court majority, Justice Samuel Alito said that the 1973 Roe ruling and repeated subsequent high court decisions reaffirming Roe "must be overruled" because they were "egregiously wrong," the arguments "exceptionally weak" and so "damaging" that they amounted to "an abuse of judicial authority."
            The decision, most of which was leaked in early May, means that abortion rights will be rolled back in nearly half of the states immediately, with more restrictions likely to follow. For all practical purposes, abortion will not be available in large swaths of the country. The decision may well mean too that the court itself, as well as the abortion question, will become a focal point in the upcoming fall elections and in the fall and thereafter.</br></item>
        <item>Google is pausing its artificial intelligence tool Gemini’s ability to generate images of people after it was blasted on social media for producing historically inaccurate images that largely showed people of color in place of White people.The embarrassing blunder shows how AI tools still struggle with the concept of race. OpenAI’s Dall-E image generator, for example, has taken heat for perpetuating harmful racial and ethnic stereotypes at scale. Google’s attempt to overcome this, however, appears to have backfired and made it difficult for the AI chatbot to generate images of White people.Gemini, like other AI tools such as ChatGPT, is trained on vast troves of online data. Experts have long warned that AI tools therefore have the potential to replicate the racial and gender biases baked into that information.When prompted by CNN on Wednesday to generate an image of a pope, for example, Gemini produced an image of a man and a woman, neither of whom were White. Tech site The Verge also reported that the tool produced images of people of color in response a prompt to generate images of a “1943 German Soldier.”
        </item>
        <item>“Madame Web” swung to No. 2 at the US box office its opening week, but landed with just $26.2 million in gross domestic sales, according to Comscore estimates Monday, compared to the strong opening for “Bob Marley: One Love.”The latest in a pattern of increasingly anemic live-action comic book adaptations, “Madame Web” now holds the record for the lowest-ever superhero box office opening from Sony Pictures.The studio has held the film rights for Spider-Man since 1999. Although it agreed to share the rights with Disney’s Marvel Studios in 2015, allowing Spidey to catapult into the Marvel Cinematic Universe, Sony still holds the rights to a wide portfolio of less popular Spider-Man-adjacent characters like Venom, Morbius, Spider-Woman and Madame Web.
 </item>
        <item>It’s an important question that Meta has conspicuously left unanswered, despite the Mark Zuckerberg-led social giant vowing last week to clamp down on the topic across both Instagram and Threads — an extraordinary move that will have far-reaching and significant consequences for the public discourse. In a series of posts announcing the policy, Adam Mosseri, the Meta executive who oversees both Instagram and Threads, said the company does not want to “proactively amplify political content from accounts you don’t follow.” Mosseri said that the platforms will still show users content from the accounts they have chosen to follow but added that the company will “avoid recommending political content” to the broader masses.“Our goal is to preserve the ability for people to choose to interact with political content, while respecting each person’s appetite for it,” Mosseri explained.The sweeping and opaque decision to reduce certain content it deems undesirable further extends Meta’s announcement in the fall that Threads is “not going go to amplify news on the platform,” sending chills through the community, much of which had just fled Elon Musk’s X for a stable platform to share information. </item>
        <item>The traditional diet of northern Portugal and northwestern Spain, known as the Southern European Traditional Atlantic Diet, or Atlantic diet for short, may hold some clues to better heart health and a lower risk of dying early from cancer, heart disease or any cause, according to studies conducted in Europe.“This is an important study because it confirms that the principles of the Traditional Mediterranean Diet (which has been studied most intensively) can be applied to other cultures as well,” said leading nutrition researcher Dr. Walter Willett, a professor of epidemiology and nutrition at Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health and professor of medicine at Harvard Medical School in Boston, in an email. He was not involved in the study.Eating a low-carb diet based on meat? You may gain weight later on, study findsBecause it’s plant-based and locally sourced, the Atlantic diet also helps protect the planet by contributing to the United Nations’ Sustainable Development Goals, the study’s authors noted.“This is a nice demonstration that such a diet, with an emphasis on local sourcing to the extent practical, offers benefits to people and planet alike. That’s a good take-away,” said Dr. David Katz, a specialist in preventive and lifestyle medicine who founded the nonprofit True Health Initiative, a global coalition of experts dedicated to evidence-based lifestyle medicine. He was also not involved in the study.
What is the Atlantic diet?The Atlantic diet includes fresh fish, particularly cod, with some red meat and pork products, dairy, legumes, fresh vegetables, potatoes typically eaten in vegetable soups, whole-grain bread, and moderate wine consumption. While some of the menu may be unique to that part of Portugal and Spain, a similar diet can be found in some parts of Czechia, Poland and the UK, experts say.In comparison, the award-winning Mediterranean diet is plant-based, with the majority of each meal focused on fruits and vegetables, whole grains, beans and seeds, with a few nuts and a heavy emphasis on extra-virgin olive oil.  </item>
        <item>Daniela Klette, a member of Germany’s notorious Red Army Faction (RAF) militant group, has been arrested in Berlin after decades on the run from armed robbery and attempted murder charges, prosecutors said on Tuesday.The arrest comes after a broadcast two weeks ago on the cold case show Aktenzeichen XY, in which a police appeal for information about three members of the group who are still at large, yielded 250 tips.Markus Heusler, the prosecutor on the case, confirmed that the woman detained on Monday, now aged 65, was Klette.She, along with the two other remaining fugitives from the gang, Burkhard Garweg and Ernst-Volker Staub, belong to the group’s so-called third generation.Founded by Andreas Baader and Ulrike Meinhof, among others, the far-left RAF’s first generation committed at least 33 murders of public officials, police, business leaders and US soldiers during its 1970s heyday and took many more hostages.The charges facing Klette, along with Garweg and Staub, relate to millions of euros’ worth of armed robberies and at least one attempted murder committed between 1999 and 2016.But these crimes were not committed in RAF’s name: the group wound itself up in 1998, sending an anonymous letter to Reuters’ office in Cologne in which the remaining members declared that “the urban guerrilla group in the form of the RAF is now history.”  </item>
        <item>The Nigeria Customs Service has paused the sale of seized bags of rice to needy residents amid growing hunger in the country, after confirming people were trampled to death during a deadly crowd surge at its Lagos office Friday.In a statement late Monday, the service confirmed multiple eyewitness reports that people died and others were injured in the Friday crush, but did not specify the number of victims.“Unforeseen challenges arose when we ran out of stock and announced the continuation of the exercise the following day, leading to a regrettable outcome,” spokesperson for the service, Abdullahi Maiwada, said in the statement.
Bags of confiscated rice for sale are seen in Lagos, Nigeria, in this photo shared by Nigeria Customs services on February 23, 2024.Related article Nigeria customs investigates deadly crowd crush during sale of seized bags of rice“The crowd became desperate and charged through our barricades in search of rice bags inside emptied containers. In the stampede that ensued, some fatalities and injuries were regrettably recorded,” Maiwada added, announcing “the suspension of this exercise until we establish what transpired.Thousands thronged the Lagos customs office - each struggling to grab a bag of the 25-kilogram (55-pound) rice selling at a discounted price of 10,000 naira ($6.80) as the price of food continues to skyrocket in Africa’s most populous country.The cost of rice, a staple food in the West African country, has surged in recent months and is now priced at more than N70,000 naira ($47.60) per 50-kilogram bag, compared to a range of 45,000 to 50,000 naira previously. Nigeria is battling one of its worst cost-of-living crises that has seen inflation rise to nearly 30% - the highest in 30 years.Its local currency has also plummeted, losing more than half its value to the US dollar, further compounding the woes of the country’s imports-driven economy.  </item>
        <item>A massive blaze that’s raging out of control is threatening Texas Panhandle towns and forcing residents to evacuate.The Smokehouse Creek Fire, the largest wildfire burning in the region, has exploded to 200,000 acres since igniting Monday afternoon, according to the Texas AM Forest Service.The blaze, driven by gusty winds and fueled by dry, unseasonably warm conditions, is moving incredibly rapidly and remains 0% contained.Evacuations were ordered early Tuesday afternoon for parts of Hemphill and Roberts counties as the fire encroached on populated areas. This includes the town of Canadian, Texas, around an hour and half northeast of Amarillo, Texas.Parts of Fritch, Texas, which straddles Moore and Hutchinson counties to the north of Amarillo, are also under an evacuation order for a separate fire, city officials and the Texas AM Forest Service said.Around 100 people could be affected by the evacuation order, Moore County Emergency Management Coordinator Tommy brooks told CNN.A robust cold front is forecast to slice through the area Tuesday evening and will cause the wind direction to shift, which could force fires to spread in new directions.  </item>
        <item>Starbucks said Tuesday it will begin talks with the Workers United union to discuss bargaining agreements and union organizing.“We have agreed with Workers United that we will begin discussions on a foundational framework designed to achieve collective bargaining agreements, including a fair process for organizing, and the resolution of some outstanding litigation,” the company said in a statement.Starbucks also said it is using the framework to begin to resolve litigation related to partner benefits announced in May 2022 and the use of the Starbucks brand in an intellectual property lawsuit.“As a sign of good faith, Starbucks has agreed to provide partners represented by Workers United with the May 2022 benefits, including credit card tipping,” the statement said.In November, thousands of Starbucks workers at hundreds of stores went on strike, protesting the lack of their first contract despite a nearly two-year organizing drive.Since the first location voted to unionize in December 2021, Starbucks has fought aggressively against the union drive. The NLRB has said that in some cases, the company engaged in illegal practices, with Starbucks refuting these claims. </item>
        <item>Many more new 401(k) “millionaires” were created last year, but the overall number remains low, according to data released Tuesday. Thanks to strong performances in stocks and bonds in 2023, coupled with steady savings rates and employer-provided matching contributions, 401(k) investors ended 2023 very much in the black.That’s according to new fourth-quarter data from Fidelity Investments, one of the largest providers of workplace retirement plans that cover 23 million 401(k) participants.The average 401(k) balance rose to $118,600 at the end of the fourth quarter, up 14% for the year.Among Gen Xers, the demographic cohort that will start retiring over the next decade, Fidelity found that the average 401(k) balance topped $500,000 among those who have been saving for at least 15 years consecutively.Fidelity also reported that the number of 401(k) accounts with balances of at least $1 million rose in the fourth quarter by 20%, to 422,000 accounts; and by 41% for the whole year. The average account balance for this group was $1,551,300 in the fourth quarter. </item>
        <item> The coveted Southwest Companion Pass is an elite travel benefit that’s almost too good to be true. This pass allows another passenger to fly with you for free (plus taxes) an unlimited number of times for the life of the pass. Traditionally, the pass is valid for the rest of the year it’s earned, plus the entire following year.The one main rule of the Companion Pass is there must be at least one seat available for sale in any fare class on a flight for which you’ve purchased your own ticket, either with cash or Southwest points.On a standard-length Companion Pass, you’re allowed to change your companion up to three times per year (not including the initial companion), meaning in theory you could have as many as seven people as your companion over two calendar years.Normally, to earn the pass, you must earn 135,000 qualifying points or fly 100 qualifying flights with Southwest in a calendar year. These points can be earned in three ways: paid flights booked through Southwest, base points earned from Rapid Rewards partners and points earned on Southwest credit cards.  </item>
    </string-array>
    <integer-array name="data_photo">
        <item>@drawable/one</item>
        <item>@drawable/two</item>
        <item>@drawable/three</item>
        <item>@drawable/four</item>
        <item>@drawable/five</item>
        <item>@drawable/six</item>
        <item>@drawable/seven</item>
        <item>@drawable/eight</item>
        <item>@drawable/nine</item>
        <item>@drawable/ten</item>
        <item>@drawable/eleven</item>
        <item>@drawable/twelve</item>
    </integer-array>
</resources>